[1] M. E. J. Newman, Networks: An Introduction, Oxford University Press, 2010.
There are many systems of interest to scientists that are composed of individual parts or components
linked together in some way. Examples include the Internet, a collection of computers linked by data
connections, and human societies, which are collections of people linked by acquaintance or social
interaction. pp.11

One of the best known and most widely studied examples of a network is the Internet, the
computer data network in which the vertices are computers and the edges are physical data
connections between them, such as optical fiber cables or telephone lines. pp.12


[2] Nam Khanh Vu, Robustness of Interconnected Complex Networks with Directed Dependency, June 2017.
In the modern world, however, it is difficult to find a network that is truly isolated.
It is important to not only study the properties of a network, but also how it couples
and interacts with other physical and abstract entities. pp.2

[18] Tomasini, Marcello. (2015). An Introduction to Multilayer Networks. 10.13140/RG.2.2.16830.18243, 2015.
Recently, a large body of research in the field has been devolved to improve and generalize existing
tools to the case of networks with multiple subsystems and layers of connectivity. Although terminology
varies broadly, accordingly to each specific case, such networks can be generally referred to as multilayer
networks. pp.1

[19] M. De Domenico et al. Mathematical Formulation of Multilayer Networks, Physical Review X 3, 041022, 2013.
The quantitative study of networks is fundamental for the study of complex systems throughout the biological, social,
information, engineering, and physical sciences  pp.1


[3] Kim Sangwoo, Structure and dynamics of complex networks, Yonsei Univ, 2012.
바라바시 알버트 모형은 계속해서 노드가 추가되는 성장하는 네트워크
(growing network)이고, 노드들 간의 연결은 선호적 연결(preferential
attachment)을 가지고 있다. pp.10

네트워크의 종류는 크게 규칙적 네트워크(regular network), 무작위
네트워크(random network)[28], 좁은 세상 네트워크(small world
network)[90]와 척도없는 네트워크(scale free network)[8] 등으로 나
눌 수 있다. pp. 8


[4] S. Boccaletti et al. The structure and dynamics of multilayer networks, Physics Reports 544, 1, 2014.

If we just turn our eyes to the immense majority of phenomena that occur around us (from those
influencing our social relationships, to those transforming the overall environment where we live, to even
those affecting our own biological functioning), we realize immediately that they are nothing but the result of
the emergent dynamical organization of systems that, on their turn, involve a multitude of basic constituents
(or entities) interacting with each other via somehow complicated patterns. pp.4

If the success of a scientific theory can be assessed by its contributions to the understanding of realworld problems, 
complex networks can possibly be seen as one of the most prosperous developments in the
last decades, having found applications in a plethora of different contexts [420]. Nevertheless, it is usually
recognized that the traditional network representation is an oversimplification of the corresponding system;
for instance, social interactions seldom develop on a single channel, and more than one relationship can bind
pairs of people. It is thus not surprising that multilayer networks have raised a great expectation, as they
should be able to better represent the topology and dynamics of real-world systems. pp.123


[5] A. Halu, K. Zhao et al. Dynamic interdependence and competition in multilayer networks, EPL(Europhysics Letters) 102, 16002, URL http://stacks.iop.org/0295-5075/102/i=1/a=16002, pp.1-5, 2013.

Interacting and interdependent networks have recently attracted great attention. pp.1

We have shown that there isa wide region in the phase diagram where two antagonistic
parties survive gathering a finite fraction of the votes, and therefore the existence of pluralism in the election system.
Moreover, we have pointed out that a key quantity to get a finite share of the overall votes is the connectivity of the
networks corresponding to different parties. Nevertheless, connectivity is not sufficient to win the elections, since a
small fraction of committed agents is sufficient to invert the results of the voting process. pp.5


[6] G. Bianconi, Multilayer Networks: Structure and Function, Oxford University Press, 2018.
chapter 4. multilayer Network in Nature, Society and infrastructures pp.
4.4 Complex infrastructures pp.79-99


In the last decade, there has been a surge in interest in modelling social network dynamics,
including opinion dynamics, election models and game theory approaches. pp.343

Here we assume that the coevolving voter model node update of a given layer α consists
in the following dynamics:
(a) a random node i of the chosen layer α is selected;
(b) its state is compared with the state of a random neighbour j on the same layer α;
(c) if node i and node j are in the same dynamical state nothing happens; otherwise
with probability 1−p[α] node i copies the state of node j, or else with probability
p[α] it severs the connection with node j.    pp.347

 
[4] Barabasi, A. L., and Albert, R., Emergence of Scaling in Random Networks, Science 286, 509, DOI: 10.1126/science.286.5439.509, 1999.

[8] Bela Bollobas, Random Graphs, 2nd edition, Cambridge University Press, section 2.4: Random Regular Graphs, 2001.
    
    Random regular network explanation
  

[9] Mikko Kivela et al. Multilayer Networks. SSRN Electronic Journal. 2. DOI : 10.1093/comnet/cnu016, 2013.

Network theory is an important tool for describing and analyzing complex systems throughout the social,
biological, physical, information, and engineering sciences.  pp.2

As research on complex systems has matured, it has become increasingly essential to move beyond simple
graphs and investigate more complicated but more realistic frameworks. pp.2

Reducing a social system to a network in which actors are connected in
a pairwise fashion by only a single type of relationship is often an extremely crude approximation of reality.
As a result, sociologists recognized decades ago that it is crucial to study social systems by constructing
multiple social networks using different types of ties among the same set of individuals. pp.2


[11] C. E. La Rocca et al. The influence of persuasion in opinion formation and polarization, Europhys. Lett. 106, 40004, pp.1-2, 2014. 

i) Compromise: if they have opposite orientations, their intensities decrease in one unit with probability q
ii) Persuasion: if they have the same orientation, their intensities increase by one unit with probability p:
pp.1 - pp.2

 When compromise events are more frequent than persuasive events, opinions are grouped around moderate values, 
leading to a centralized state of opinions. In the opposite case, if persuasion events dominate over compromise events, 
opinions are driven towards extreme positive and negative values, inducing polarization. pp.6

[12] Alvarez-Zuzek et al. Interacting Social Processes on Interconnected Networks. PLoS ONE. 11. 10.1371/journal.pone.0163593, 2016.

Node i in network B: the state of i changes with probability. pp.5

As we have shown, this is due to the fact that increasing the level of opinion reinforcement in network A beyond a value r
 produces a large number of positive extremists that are able to resist the change of orientation, imposing their positive orientation 
to the entire system. Besides, the study of the fullr − β phase space revealed a transition at a critical threshold βc, 
from a disordered phase where both orientations coexist to an ordered phase characterized by a consensus of one 
of the two orientations. We also showed that both dynamics are equivalent along the crossover line (r, β) that separates the 
A-dominance and B-dominance regions, as the consensus probability in either state is the same on the (r, β) line.  pp.14


[13] Gomez-Gardenes J et al. Layer-layer competition in multiplex complex networks. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A 373:20150117, 2015.
Our results show that, regardless of the average connectivity and total strength of the leading layer 
(the one that focuses all the activity for small inter-layer coupling), it is its minimum degree that causes nodes to start to 
use the other layer, i.e. controls the onset of the transition from localized to mixed activity. On the other hand, 
it is the average degree of the leading layer that controls when the state of full mixing is reached. These two results point out 
that the transition from localized to mixed activity occurs via a cascade from poorly connected nodes in the leading layers
 (the ones that obtain more benefits from leaving first the leading layer) to those highly connected ones 
(being the ones that are less prone to leave the layer in which they are well connected). Thus, the larger the average degree of 
the leading layer, the more inter-layer coupling is needed to persuade all the degree classes to leave the localized state. pp.7 - 8.

[14] H.T. Diep et al. Dynamics of two-group conflicts: A statistical physics model, Physica A, http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2016.10.072, 2017.  
Social conflicts have been extensively studied theoretically and practically by scholars in sociology, social psychology as well as
negotiation and decision making. There is broad consensus in the literature that social conflicts are complex, and therefore their 
outcomes are difficult to predict.  pp.1.

[15] M Abrams et al. Modelling the dynamics of language death. Nature.424.900. DOI : 10.1038/424900a, 2003.
1장짜리 아티클

[17] F. Vazquez et al. Agent based models of language competition: macroscopic descriptions and order–disorder transitions, Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment 2010, P04007, 2010.
The Abrams and Strogatz model pp.4




